KARTHIKA VENKATA CHELLAPATHI

Canning Vale, WA 6155 || 0472688120 || <u>karthikav.rmkcse@gmail.com</u> <u>www.linkedin.com/in/karthika-v-chellapathi</u>

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Dedicated and knowledgeable software Engineer with 4 years of extensive experience in the field of software development providing engineering solutions for banking customers. My area of expertise is effective analysis of system requirements and implementation of the developed software components along with assisting application integration. I am aspiring to re-enter the IT industry after a career break. Currently, I am doing SheCodes Plus Perth 2022 program on Emergence Scholarship to improvise my technical skills.

KEY SKILLS

Information Technology ~ Root Cause Analysis ~ Quality Control ~ Creativity ~ Verbal & Written communication ~ Troubleshooting ~ Time Management ~ Presentation skills ~ Self-Motivated ~ Problem-solving ~ Teamwork ~ Critical Thinking ~ Analytical Skills

TOOLS & SOFTWARE

HTML, CSS, Python, Django, Java, Javascript

EDUCATION

Master of Science (Software Systems) | The Birla Institute of Technology & Science, India (Dec 2013) Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Science) | Anna University, India (April 2009)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Education Assistant - Leeming SHS Education Support Centre

Feb 2022 – Current

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Responsible for assisting teachers in a classroom setting to deliver planned education lessons to children.
- Managing daily work volumes and achieving teaching outcomes in timely manner.
- Demonstrated the ability to work with special needs students and provide one on one educational support to students.
- Accountable for cultivating and maintaining key relationships with education providers, teachers, and students.

Education Assistant - Armadale Education Support Centre

Nov 2021 – Mar 2022

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Responsible for assisting teachers in delivering planned lessons in place of a regular education assistant.
- Assisted special needs students having physical and mental disabilities in their learning program.
- Improved the learning outcome for students with disabilities via empathic communication allowing the
 center to fully understand their hardship circumstances and co-operatively solve problems with students
 and families.

Career break Nov 2013 – Jun 2019

Break for family responsibilities.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Demonstrated understanding of the business requirements and proposed implementations based on client inputs.
- Developed business logic adhering to business standards along with component testing and assisted maintenance of delivered products in the production server.
- Involved in defect fixing activity during system Integration testing and supported in handling major issues during project release.
- Effectively interacting with global customers and ensuring consistency and quality of developmental activities driving towards the highest levels of customer satisfaction.
- Researched and developed reusable software components to reduce costs and improving productivity for clients.
- Ensured successful and on-time completion of the tasks along with compliance to scope and cost specifications of project.

Key Projects/Assignments:

1. Citibank EMEA &APAC project

Role: Development Lead

Client: Citi Bank Corp NA

Jan 2013 – Nov 2013

- Responsible to work on software development to enhance the Citibank Internet application pages for EMEA&APAC countries, as part of Citi Global product development. The project focuses on fraud/risk transactions in payments module and generate report based on the customer response. The project was done using struts framework in Java.
- Demonstrated understanding of requirements, paying attention to details in the business requirements, and provide feasible solutions.
- Resourcing, guiding and mentoring team of engineers technically in their day-to-day activities.

2. Forget User Id &Password – Mobile Apps

Role: Software Developer

Client: Citi Bank Corp NA

Aug 2012 – Jan 2013

- Responsible to work on forget user ID and password flow using web Service communication for private label credit card customer in mobile applications and return the service response to mobile application development team.
- Reviewing the developed code, unit testing and ownership of the assigned functionality.
- Release support and handling major issues during production.

3. Single Portal Flexibility

Role: Software Developer

Client: Citi Bank Corp NA

Nov 2010 - Aug 2012

- This Agile developmental project was to integrate the credit card portal application with a banking (checking / savings account) portal application, as part of global operating model of the banking system. Worked in the development team to migrate the credit card applications on the banking host application. The project was done using struts framework in Java.
- Assisted in development of reusable components for certain additional features in existing credit card application and help them integrate with the banking system.
- Worked on revamping the banking application pages using HTML/CSS to offer customers with simple, flexible, and new UI.

4. Credit Card Application -Servicing

Role: Software Developer

Client: Citi Bank Corp NA

Nov 2009 – *Nov* 2010

- Involved in all the phases of software development cycle in waterfall model and supported the maintenance of the entire application.
- Worked on minor functionality changes and defect fixing activities.
- Developed changes to provide rich UI to customers.

Key Achievements

- Recognized by organization for working seamlessly in an Agile project and was awarded On-spot award.
- Achieved KPI's relating to on-time project delivery, practicing appropriate work ethics and established successful career growth as per organization standards.

ADDITIONAL TRAINING AND QUALIFICATIONS

SheCodes Plus Perth 2022 program – Web development training (Sep 2022- Apr 2023)

Certified Tester Foundation Level (CTFL)- ISTQB - Jun 2022.

Certificate IV in School Based Education Support - Institute of Teacher Aide Courses – (Nov 2021 - Nov 2022)

Mentor Volunteer – EdConnect Australia – (Jul 2021 – Aug 2022)

Cyber Safety Professional Development - WA Child Safety services - Nov 2021

Certificate III in Education Support - South Metropolitan TAFE – (July 2019 - Dec 2019)

REFEREES

Referees Available Upon Request